LAURA SOFIA MEDINA ARANGUREN

PROGRAMMER | WEBMASTER | FULL- STACK DEVELOPER | DATA SCIENTIST

• **Phone** 3046298705 • **E-mail**: sofiaranguren21@gmail.com Bogotá, Colombia

PROFILE:

A young 22-year-old adult, bilingual in English and Spanish and eager to work in jobs regarding computer programming, data analysis or web development.

Highly oriented to results, with excellent interpersonal relationships, productive, proactive, organized, creative, innovative, responsible, hard working and disciplined.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

2021-2023

• Bilingual B2+ agent for the company Teleperformance, managing money handling systems, user verification support, data filtration, risk agent and customer service.

Volunteers

2017-2021

- Translator from English to Spanish and vice versa for foreign people visiting the church.
- Volunteer to direct and guide a worship music band in Orlando/Florida, serving and helping people of all ranges of ages.
- Volunteer to visit and support hospitals and elder communities in Bogotá, Colombia.

2021-2023

Volunteer to manage external hardware systems, mixing desks as
Ableton Live for a church in live events such as concerts, plays, etc.

EDUCATION AND ACADEMIC FORMATION:

Graduated from 12th grade from the school **Abeka Academy**, January 2021. With a 3.85 GPA and with a 1170 SAT score (Math:600; Evidence Based Reading and Writing: 570).

Currently doing junior year on Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence in the

Related Coursework:

- Algorithmic thinking.
- Computational science.
- Computer networks.
- Algorithms analysis.
- Linear data structures.
- Non-linear data structures.
- Machine learning optimization.
- Databases.
- Operating systems.
- Programming and transduction languages.
- Supervised machine learning.
- KNN, classification and regression.
- Neural networks in image recognition.

Specific Coursework:

- HTML/HTML5
- CSS/CSS3
- SemanticUI
- Responsive Design
- Flexbox
- CSS Grid
- Bootstrap 5
- DOM Manipulation
- Javascript (including ES6/ES7/ES8/ES9/ES10/ES2020/ES2021/ES2022)
- Asynchronous JavaScript
- HTTP/JSON/AJAX
- React + Redux + React Hooks
- Git + Github
- Spring Boot and Angular
- Command Line
- Node.js
- Express.js
- NPM
- RESTful API Design
- PostgresSQL
- SQL
- Authentication
- Authorization
- Scalable Infrastructure

- Security
- Production and Deployment
- Python
- Java
- C++
- C#

Relevant Coursework:

- Keyboarding. 2020
- Speech. 2020
- English Literature and grammar 2018-2020
- Business math. 2018
- Python Certificate. 2022
- Kaggle Pandas certificate. 2023
- Oracle database programming and designing. 2023
- UdemyFull-stack development. 2023